Welcome back to Way North West. If
you own antiques and you wondered what
they're worth, our next guest is here
to share helpful tips on how you can
figure that all out. We welcome back
antique appraiser Gary Germer. Great to see
you again. Um okay, so we had employees
pull out um their favorite items that
they think, I don't know if it's worth
anything or not, but maybe you can help
us and give us tips along the way as
to how we can figure it out in general,
right? >> Yeah. >> Okay, so let's start
with this. I know I think I've told you
that I have a uh a great aunt who was
a lieutenant commander in the Navy.
>> Okay. >> So she brought home these
things and kind of wondering, I love them,
but >> Absolutely. >> anything? >> Your
tea set here, probably she had a whole
set at one time. They were
sold usually in sets with six,
you know, uh dessert plates, six cups
and and and saucers and etc. This
is Japanese and it's called uh Satsuma
is the type of of finish on it.
>> Oh, wow. >> You see the little guys
in there with little gold halos around
let you know that they're that they're
either saints or heavenly people.
>> Okay. >> And um this was made
for the American market and to sell
usually at PX or at shops in uh
Tokyo or or Hong Kong. >> Right.
>> When guys were on vacation, they
would bring these sets home. Difference
between an American set and a Japanese
set in the is the style. The cup has
a handle on it. Uh Japanese or an Asian
tea cups never have handles. >> handles
on it. You're right. >> theory that
it's too hot to pick up, it's too hot to
drink. >> Yeah. >> And so, being
Americans, we don't care. >> Right.
Yeah. >> And the fact that it's in sets
of even numbers, Japanese or in Asian
sets even numbers are bad luck, so their
sets are always odd numbers. So you
would get >> seven or nine in a set where
we get six or eight in a set. >> think
that's worth something or not? >> I think
they're they be they they kind of hit
it um went down and now they've come back
up. The ones that bring the most have
dragons cuz people like dragons. >> yeah.
I got it. >> And so it's a stylistic
thing. But a whole set like that, if
you have the pot and all about $200, you
know, so a little place setting like >>
How do you figure that out? Do you go
online? >> Well, you know, we have a tool
called eBay, which is really great to
work with. >> Right. >> Um because you
go and you hit there they have a search
engine and you can hit their advanced
search. Put in what you're looking for.
And then scroll on to sold. Don't
just hit any, hit sold. And it'll show
you what's sold cuz people ask all kind
they'll ask $10,000 for a set. Well,
that doesn't mean it's worth $10,000 if
no one's buying it. >> Right, for sure.
>> it goes. And that's a great one. If
you want to pay for if you're working for
a whole estate on a whole estate, your
grandma's estate, pay for a website for a
month or two called WorthPoint. >>
WorthPoint, okay. >> It shows you auction
records of all sorts of things. And those
two can get you quite a ways. >> Okay.
Here's some Bleek, Irish Bleek. >> The
Bleek and Hummels were really hot with
our parents. >> Right. >> And with our
kids don't want them. And that's kind of
the subject that keeps coming up because
our lifestyle has changed. Plus the fun
of collecting was searching for it.
And um >> Which was a big thing. That I
mean, if you think about it, bargain
hunters are people who love to collect
things. Yeah, that's That's the idea. >>
Go to the ant estate sales and antique
shops, whatever, and ferret it out.
Now you can go on eBay and click in an
afternoon have a whole collection of
Hummels or whole sets of >> so they're not
worth very much anymore. >> They just
They just tanked, really. And uh you know,
cuz the fun's in the hunt, not in the
owning, you know. >> Right, got you. I
understand that. Now these are pretty
interesting, rolling pins. >> Yeah, these
are fun. Now people are collecting and
I don't want to say that there aren't
People are collecting all kinds of things
and like the kitchen stuff still stays
pretty strong. These are really good
uh rolling pins for on the collector's
level. Your Your back one here, a narrow
wood handled, this is from the 19th
century. >> Wow. >> On the at auction
or at a shop, you'll see this going
anywhere from a hundred to to two hundred
dollars. But the advertising ones here
on the um on the ceramic pins
are really uh collectible.
And this one is from a little town in
Iowa and uh the producer brought this set
told me that that was her grandmother's
hometown or something like that. >> So
that makes it even more interesting. If
it's from a town that no longer exists,
>> Yeah. >> then the price goes through
the moon. >> So like what are you
thinking for this? >> This town exists,
that would be anywhere from four to six
hundred dollars. >> Wow. >> For uh an
advertising piece like that. They're
terrible for using if you could do any
cooking. >> No. Yeah, I can see that. I
think they're pretty cool.
>> Yeah, they're really cool.
Pearls, you'll This is something I
think that people make who are in the
business and are going out to estate
sales all the time make the most money on
is jewelry and picking up jewelry cuz
there's people won't look to see if
there's gold or silver or what it is and
they'll just put out even professional
sales I've known people who've picked up
pieces that are, you know, a friend of
mine picked up a diamond uh and platinum
ring for um uh eight dollars. >> Oh my
gosh. >> at at a sale. It was in a
little ziplock bag and we thought it was
costume jewelry. >> Oh my gosh. >>
This particular strand is um freshwater
pearls. You can see they're irregularly
shaped. >> Right. >> And they put a
little seed in in the in the in the uh
oyster and they're they produce them a
lot. This strand there,
not particularly valuable.
Um probably in the twenty to
thirty dollar range on that.
>> What you want are the perfectly round
ones. >> Perfectly round. And this uh
tea kettle >> Yeah, she was one of
the This is fun. It's a little almost
child-size tea little teapot, but what
makes it interesting, I mean, it's just a
little aluminum pot, but it's um
a commemorative from the English
I I my glasses off. I forgot. It's 1951
English uh um celebration.
>> Okay. >> And um
and it has Big Ben skyline. Well, this
is great. If you're going to be working
on an estate, invest in a loop. >>
Okay. >> You know. >> That's what it's
called, is a loop. >> And I have one
that's a three-powered one that I carry
around. They're not expensive. You can
get them at Fred Meyer. You can get >> a
big mag- magnifying >> Magnifying glass.
So you can like read the marks on your
Hummel's. Back to your Hummel's. Those
are early ones. The Belleek The Belleek
is a black mark. Those are going to
have more value than more modern made
pieces. >> Got you. >> This is fun in
England. Here nobody cares that there was
a celebration in England in 1951.
You know, and even at that, they're
interested in it for like $10. >> Got you.
>> The little dolls are from France.
They're from Southeast France from the
Provence region. Um and
they're called Santons.
S S A T uh S S A N T O N uh dolls.
And they have all kinds of of local uh
uh wear. They >> Yeah, the wardrobes
>> and stuff. Very collected. They're
still collected. You can find them online
anywhere These would sell probably in
the 50 a piece range. >> Yeah. >> You'll
see them going up for as much as two,
three hundred dollars for more elaborately
larger ones and more elaborately made
ones. And condition means all. These are
in just beautiful shape. The fabric and
all is really great on them. So that's
why >> lastly, the statue. This is from
Germany. >> This is a German piece um
and it's a Blanc de Chine, the all white.
You You always You see people will turn
things over. I've actually spilled food
on myself at a dinner party once.
Oh, what's on this plate? You know.
And so you look to see and it's made
in Western Germany. Which lets you know
that was a short period of time right
after the war. And it's a secondary
company though. It's It's Meissen
uh was is the top and then this would
have been the same district uh of of
Germany. And these you have to really
look these over cuz often times cuz they
have so many things sticking out, they'll
be um little chips and stuff. >> Yeah,
I got you. >> Anyway, it's a it's a pretty
little piece. People in America don't
seem to understand German porcelain like
that. But that would be about 75 to 100
dollars. >> So, eBay
pay for worthpoint.com is a good one to
go for and books you say abebooks.com,
right? >> Yeah, abebooks.com
to research this. >> also
website for art, mutualart.com.
>> Mutual art is one that you can it's
a pay site. The the books one is not a
pay site but mutual art is a pay site
but if you're going to be taking care of
an estate, pay for it for a month. You
can just buy a month. >> I got you. So,
we're going to put those
sites on our website at katu.com. Gary,
thank you very much. Very informative. I
appreciate it. All right,